Anna Klymenko

Customer-Centric Web Developer

Full-stack web developer with over 5+ years of experience analyzing, designing, developing, and integrating front-end & back-end-based applications, Possesses knowledge of web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, AngularJS, Ajax, and PHP. Key achievement: created a web application that allowed 75K users to search for nearby restaurants based on their location with 89% accuracy.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Web Developer

November 2015 - Present

- Leveraged web technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript to create dynamic, interactive user interfaces.
- Worked and created an e-commerce website using PHP, MySQL, and JavaScript within 3 months.
- Developed a responsive email template in HTML5 and CSS3 that increased the clickthrough rate by 78%, an improvement from previous years.
- Developed a full stack application using Node.js, AngularJS, and MongoDB to enable users to interact with a dynamic content management system.

Front End Developer

February 2013 – October 2015

- Developed front-end code using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery to create a responsive web application that works across 29 devices, including desktops and tablets.
- Optimized 29 web pages for speed and performance by eliminating unnecessary scripts/styles and increasing load time by 69%.
- Created an interactive map for a real estate company's website that allowed 7K users to search by neighborhood and get real-time feedback about a property.
- Partnered with 28 UX designers on redesigning Growth existing site improving conversion rate by 77%.

Backend Developer

June 2015 – January 2016

- Supported the development of 28 new features such as user authentication & authorization, course management system (CMS), and student information system (SIS) by designing APIs for an Edtech site.
- Developed a microservices-based architecture with Node.js, Kubernetes, Docker, MySQL/PostgreSQL, and Elasticsearch for 15 online education platforms that serve 1.5M users hourly.
- Developed a backend solution to increase system efficiency by 20%, resulting in faster completion of projects.

CONTACT

Litvinivska,26
Bahata Cherneshchyna, Kharkiv Ukraine
•joypender@outlook.com

SKILLS

Technical Skills:

- Bootstrap (Advanced)
- WordPress (Experienced)
- •Web Design
- ReactJs,AngularJs,NodeJs
- Django

Industry Knowledge:

- Amazon Web Services
- •Front-end Development
- •Web Applications

Tools and Software:

- jQuery
- Linux
- Apache
- Nginx

EDUCATION

CALIFORNIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

Computer Science 2008-2012

OTHER

- •Certified in Java SE 8
- Programmer.
- •Certified Web Developer.
- •Oracle Certified Associate.